Hi! Welcome back to Jurina House!
1, 2, 3, 4
All together now
6, 7, 8, 9
Jurina~!
I'm Jurina Matsui, 23 years old
So
Today
For the first time!!
I'll be answering questions!
What questions will I get?
I'm excited
Without further ado
Let's start!
[What's your name?]
Jurina Matsui! I said it earlier!
[Didn't you hear my greeting?]
[What's the origin of your name?]
I asked my mother, she said "Ju" comes from the word "pearl"
It seems she wanted me to shine brightly like a pearl
[What's your height?]
My height is 163cm
[How old are you?]
23! I said that earlier too!
[Were you even listening?]
[When's your birthday?]
3 March (Mitsubachi)
[Your blood type?]
Type B
[Any special skills?]
Dance!
[What's special about your outfit today?]
This looks like a normal white T-shirt, but actually it's not!
Look at this! You can probably see it from behind, but there's a button here
[This week, who did you talk to on the phone for over 5 minutes?]
Grandma!
[I love her!]
[Who do you pay attention to on TikTok?]
hinata-chan!
Which YouTube channels do you like?
Yorochiki Channel! Nadal-san is hilarious
[Yakiniku or Sushi? Go.]
Ohh this one's hard
I love both but
Yakiniku!
[Favorite sports?]
Pro-wrestling, martial arts, basketball, swimming
There's so many... ball games too
I did track and field, so I like it too
[Ever had a paranormal experience?]
A lot!
Once, I went into a haunted house
Where only dolls were supposed to appear
But I felt my legs being grabbed
Another time at a hotel I stayed in
I woke up in the morning to find my towel full of blood stains
[Sweet? Spicy?]
Sweet, I'm really bad with spicy food
[Anything you want to do that you can't right now?]
Swimming, I'm so bad at it
[The world ends in 1 week!! How would you spend your final week?]
I'll eat my mom's cooking
[If you were to keep a pet, would you get a dog or a cat? Or something else?]
What do you mean, "something else?"
I already have two dogs, they're toy poodles
If I were to get a new pet
I want to try getting a cat
[What's the hardest word that you know?]
Saishokukenbi (A beautiful and talented woman)
That probably wasn't that hard...
[Who do you want to collaborate with on YouTube?]
The comedienne, Rei Maruyama
[I think it'll be fun!]
She does things like impressions of Tao Tsuchiya
I'd love to do it with her
[What do you get cravings for sometimes?]
Cup ramen! I love it!
[You finish it without realising]
[Right now, draw an animal in under a minute]
An animal?
Under a minute?
[Drawing start!]
Oh no, hold on, this isn't right
It's done!
- It's done, can I show it?
- Please
It's a cow!
[A cow with way too many spots]
[If you go on an adventure to the ends of the earth, which SKE member would you bring along?]
Haruka Kumazaki! When I'm feeling down, she'll probably cheer me up!
[Favorite song in SKE48?]
Okidoki!
[Love it!]
[If you're going to Disneyland, who would you want to go with?]
Oh that's tough
Oh! Yuna Ego, because I promised to go with her!
[Which SKE48 member would you bring for a drive all around Japan?]
Suzuran Yamauchi! We have good conversations!
She's pretty interesting too
Even if we kept driving, I wouldn't be bored I think
[Which memory with members makes you go, "that's so nostalgic"?]
When we performed as SKE48 in Nagoya Dome
In the first song, the 1st generation members stood together on stage
Whenever I meet those members
I'd think, "we worked hard for that moment on stage"
It's nostalgic
[When was the time you laughed the most in your life?]
I love Downtown, so when I'm in a TV show with the two of them
Matsumoto-san and Hamada-san, they'd do jokes in response to things people say
I'd always laugh a lot
We just heard a laugh there!
[Incredible timing]
[When was the time you cried the most in your life?]
Back when I starred in the TBS drama "Death Cash"
In a scene together with Riho Yoshioka
We cried a lot together
[When was the time you felt the most in pain in your life?]
This happens a lot while changing clothes
When we do quick-changing in concerts
The costume designer would try her best to put my shoes on me
Like for boots, the moment it's zipped up
My skin would get caught in it
That really hurts a lot
[Which photo in your phone captures an important memory for you?]
My photo with an important memory is
This one!
SKE48's new single "Koi Ochi Flag" will go on sale on 3 Feb 2021
For me it's also my graduation single
This picture is an offshot from the "Koi Ochi Flag" MV
[Who do you have trouble saying "thank you" to?]
My mother
I really love her a lot
We get along very well too
But it's because we get along that it's hard to say! It's embarrassing
Around the time I just entered SKE
My mother would be working while taking care of me
She'd always cook delicious food for me
I really want to say thank you to her for supporting me all this time
Well, I think she might watch this though
[Tell us 3 of your favorite movies]
Star Wars, Jumanji, and Ghost
[What was your favorite school event?]
I couldn't participate in most school events but
Maybe the sports festival? Because I was often number one at running
[Any embarrassing memories you want to forget?]
Once, while recording for a music show
I was the only one wearing pants instead of a skirt
It didn't stretch well
After some intense dancing
The button came flying off
[Anything you want to throw away but can't?]
I guess I can't throw away things people give me
Even for things I bought myself
I'd go, "I went through the trouble of buying it..." and be reluctant to throw them away
So basically I can't throw anything away
[What do you want to tell yourself who's in elementary and middle school]
"You know all those celebrities you see on TV?"
"You'll be appearing alongside them a lot"
[What would you do if you were to do a side gig while being an idol]
I love animals, so I'd work in a pet shop?
And if I wasn't an idol, I might have wanted to be a track and field athlete
[Any good food you'd recommend in Nagoya?]
There are sweets from this shop called Salon de Thé Nagoya France
Not many people know of it
But the sweets are really good, it'd be great if you buy them as gifts too
[Where in Nagoya would you recommend for someone to have fun?]
For a great time in Nagoya I'd recommend Oasis 21
It's beautiful at night
There are even people from overseas who come to Nagoya just to see it
I definitely recommend it!
[What's the first Aichi prefecture specialty that comes to mind? Answer right away!]
Jurina
What am I even saying
[What kinds of moments make you think "I've come back to my hometown"?]
When I'm in the SKE48 theater in Sunshine Sakae, standing on stage
Or when I'm in local Nagoya TV shows, talking with staff members
They'd say "welcome home!" to me
Those moments, I think
[You're asked to produce an event in Nagoya Castle!! What kind of event will it be?]
When we think of castles
Traditional Japanese clothing comes to mind as something that goes with it
I'd gather some cute girls
And have them wear furisode that I produced
Then have something like a fashion show
[You're running for Mayor of Nagoya! What electoral promises will you make?]
I'll make Nagoya more Nagoyaka (peaceful)
[Ba-dum-tss...?]
[From here on there will be 3 questions for a psychology test!]
[Say you were an animal in your previous life, what would you be in your next one?]
[Your answer will reveal who's most important to you in life]
Ehh?
Oh no
A) A dog or cat raised with care by humans
B) A wild beast in the savannah
C) A bird dancing in the vast skies
D) A marine creature like a dolphin
Oh, that's tough but...
The wild beast in the savannah, for sure
A) A dog or cat raised with care by humans
[Your most important person is "family"]
B) A wild beast in the savannah
[Your most important person is your "life partner"]
C) A bird dancing in the vast skies
[Your most important person is "the person who lives in your heart"]
D) A marine creature like a dolphin
[Your most important person is nobody, it's yourself]
I guess that's true
I want someone I can do my best with together
[Out of these 4, what makes you think of "trials and tribulations" the most?]
[Your answer will reveal the biggest problem you'll face in your life]
A) Dark "reinclouds"
"Rainclouds", you mean (lol)
B) Fallen rocks blocking your way
C) Endless desert
D) A battlefield
Fallen rocks blocking the way!
A) Dark rainclouds
[You are your biggest obstacle]
B) Fallen rocks blocking your way
[You are someone who aims very high]
C) Endless desert
[Your biggest barriers are love and friendship, as well as building trust with others]
D) A battlefield
[The contradiction between society and organizations, you tend to perceive gaps in preconceived notions]
That hits the nail on the head!
I'm totally that type, someone with big dreams
But I'd hate it if I don't achieve them
I'll do my best
[What pattern would you choose for an amulet pendant?]
[Your answer will tell us what you want to achieve the most in your life]
A) A four leaf clover
B) A ring
C) A rose
D) A key
A four leaf clover!
A) A four leaf clover
[You want to succeed in your career and have a definite goal you're aiming for in your profession]
B) A ring
[You are someone who is looking for true love. The ring is the symbol of love]
C) A rose
[You are trying to be the ideal version of yourself]
D) A key
[A key opens doors, and you who chose this is very likely to be thinking of opening the door to the next world]
I am somewhat of a workaholic
I'm only thinking about work
That was Jurina Matsui's 48 questions
How was it?
If you have any questions for me
I'd love for you to leave a comment!
Thank you!
Bye bye!