Hi! Welcome back to Jurina House!
And also, happy new year!
Please continue to support me this year
I'm Jurina Matsui
Thank you for everything in 2020
So it's now the year 2021
2021 is the year of the cow
Actually I was born in the year of the cow!
I haven't really mentioned this much
So some of you might be thinking "Oh, so Jurina was born in the year of the cow!"
This is my zodiac year
About how I want 2021 to be
I think that's something I need to talk about
I want to make this the year of Jurina Matsui
That's one thing
But as for what it actually means to make it my year
Honestly, I don't know yet
[You don't know?!]
Didn't the past year pass by in the blink of an eye?
It feels like only recently that I said "it's now 2020!"
When I look back at 2020
It was a difficult year, I think
I think that was the same for everyone
As for me
In 2020
I was supposed to graduate from SKE48
Also my graduation concert was to be in September
With October being when I would have my final theater performance and graduate
Unfortunately due to our current situation, we've had to postpone all of this
Currently, I still don't know when I'd be able to graduate
Really, how should I put this
It's sad
I've been part of SKE48 for 12 years
Since I was a 6th grader
And when I realized it, I turned 23
And because I've done it for so long
I was seriously worried about graduation
It was a decision I made with a lot of determination
And then announced it
That's why with these developments
I found it really unfortunate
But because of it, fans have been telling me
"We're glad we get to see the idol Jurina Matsui a little longer"
There were many people who told me that
Also in these circumstances, we can't do handshake events like before
So I've been trying a few things, like this YouTube channel
To be able to reach fans around the world
I'm happy about that
I'm taking this very positively
One reason I started this YouTube channel was also
In the midst of these difficult times in the world
I wanted to contribute things that are bright and fun, even if it's just a little
That's why I started doing this
So far I've uploaded a few videos
When I do these things in a group
There usually isn't much footage of just me alone
For example, I've been in some TV shows but
But it's not very often that I get to do things like a special feature where I get a lot of focus
Compared to that, over here I get to show many new sides of me
This is a great place to do that
That's what I think
This channel, which is called Jurina House
It's a channel that I want to create together with all of you viewers
That's one of the themes
For example, I decided on the channel name out of everyone's suggestions
And we also have the MC Puppet Mascot
It will be chosen from the drawings you all send in
We have plans like that
Make sure you don't miss it!
It would be really great if we could all do this together
If there's anything you want me to do on this channel
I'd love it for you to comment freely about it
Fortunately, I'm now on various social networking platforms
And recently there are a small number of events where I get to meet fans again directly
I hope you could start telling me your thoughts in such places
I want to keep doing things like that
So I'd be glad if you could tell me your thoughts
How was 2020 for all of you?
[I'm waiting for your comments!]
I'm actually quite curious
Right now we can't meet others, and I can't meet my fans
Don't they say "absence makes the heart grow fonder"?
But that's actually true!
It's because we can't see each other
That I realized even more how important you all are to me
I really felt it during this time
So I really want to express my gratitude to everyone who's kept supporting me
Thank you so much
Anyway since I started this YouTube channel last year
I'm now able to do the things I like doing
And show my natural side at the same time
Some people think I'm scary and harsh
Well, they're not actually wrong
When it comes to performances
I want to do it right
Because I want us to encourage and cheer up our fans
And I want us to show people that the 48 group still has momentum
That's why there are times when I'm strict towards my juniors
But actually, once our work is done, when we switch off our work mode
I'm really just like a baby
I think my fans who come to handshake events probably already know this
But I probably don't have that public image
Well, I'm hoping I get to show those sides of me through YouTube
And have people think, "oh Jurina Matsui is actually this kind of person"
I hope I manage to gradually do that in 2021
And make this the year of Jurina Matsui
I'd be glad if all of you can help me out
Please continue to support me in 2021
Also, please subscribe to my channel
And smash the like button on this video
Once again, please support me in 2021!
I hope this will be a good year for all of you!
Bye bye!
Happy new year!