[English subtitles by @kujirajuunigou]
- Good work today
- Thank you
What are your thoughts now that the performance is over?
Well, first of all
I feel like "I did it!"
And also
It was something I wanted many fans to see
I mean live, in the flesh
That's what I strongly felt
It was a concert good enough for me to feel that way
[4 October]
[The day of the "Te wo tsunaginagara" stage]
Good morning!
It's so cute
I'm performing at 11:30am
But they've been doing it since around 9
That's way too early
But because we need to fit 12 stages into 3 days
If we don't start early, we can't fit everything in
Just goes to show how much history we actually have
It's amazing when you think about it
You alright?
Ah, what happened was
- Miraculously, my hip recovered
- Really?
But now my feet are hurting instead
- So it switched places
- Maybe
Did you ice it?
Yes, I did
Good
- I'll do my best today
- I'm counting on you
This is for Halloween
- This is for Halloween?
- Yes
- I thought it was cute earlier
- It's cute!
It's a little early for this though
I cried during rehearsal
"Tooku ni itemo" (Even if you're far away) affected me most I think
It's a song we'd sing when a member graduates
On top of that, we're in these circumstances
Where we can't meet our fans
All these things came together in my mind
And my graduation is on the horizon too
Pretty soon
I'll be going far away from SKE
Just too many things like that
Were overlapping with the song
Like, I wonder if things are going to be alright
Do you have any particular thoughts about performing on stage?
Since my debut, for 12 years
What I kept in mind was
Was that I want people to watch our concerts and performances
And then for them to think
"Ah, I'll do my best tomorrow!" or something like that
I want them to get strength from watching us
When you perform you need to always stay hydrated, don't you?
Yes, yes, that's why
I normally mix a sports drink with water
About equal parts of each, and drink it
Drinking a sports drink as is would be too sweet for me
So I mix it with water before drinking
And I don't usually drink cold drinks
Just normal temperature
I'm eating brown sugar candy
- Do you usually get that brown sugar candy?
- Yes
I was actually surprised
- It's from Kikaijima, that's pretty far down the south
- Really?
- It's a delicacy from that area
- Wow, Kikaijima?
Okinawa?
- It's just across Okinawa
- Across Okinawa? Wow
Thanks for sending this from all the way there
Oh no, I'm really nervous
My stomach is acting up
Even after performing for 12 years, you still get nervous like this?
Totally
I get nervous every time
I'm probably the one who gets nervous the most
I scream in panic before the performance
For you, what's the number one moment where your switch is flipped to get geared up to perform
The moment I get geared up
I think that would be
Either the moment I step on stage or
When this music called "Overture" gets played at the start of the concert
The one that goes "SKE48~!"
The one that starts the concert, it's probably that moment
At that moment fans would do this cheer, like "sore sore sore"
At the same time I'd be backstage also going "sore sore sore"
I'd feel like "it's time to go!"
Like "it's about to start!"
It's probably that moment where I get geared up
Alright
I'll go get changed
Now that I've put my outfit on, I'm even more nervous
I'm getting super nervous
- You're nervous?
- I'm nervous
- How nervous are you, out of 100%?
- 99.9%
- Aaahh
- But if I can still say things like that I'm probably okay
- Yeah, you'll be alright
Because it's you, Jurina-san
You're cute
Even when I'm like this?
- You're like a chihuahua
- You always say that!
Your video went viral
Yeah, that's crazy isn't it?!
The one with Nami-san
- I was just thinking today that I want to do another one
- Really?
When did you film that one?
Pretty recently, around 4 or 5 days ago
I was so surprised, I didn't expect it to blow up like that
- Do you know what happened?
- No idea
There were lots of overseas fans
- Yeah, there were many comments from overseas fans
- That's right
I was so suprised
I'm happy
It went viral when I got here
Let's try to do another one
Yeah, I'll do my best
I'm so nervous
One, two...
One, two
One, two... Good!
Let's do one more
Let's do some taken from the bottom, and change up the angles
Everyone, let's pose freely
One, two...
Okay!
It was really only one shot
When they say "one shot", they'd usually take around 3
Jurina-san!
- Yes?
- It's a little late, but here's a birthday present from me
Really? (lol)
Mine was back in March (lol)
Thanks so much!
I'm happy
- Please use it if it's to your liking
- Thanks, I will. I'll look at it later
- Will you be watching Tetsuna? You'll be staying?
- Yes!
Please watch it
Tell me what you think later
You've been supporting us since way back
You're a member who also understands the feelings of fans
Thank you!
The "Te wo tsunaginagara" stage is
The first original stage we received as SKE
It was created specially for us
Including the lyrics, costumes, and the choreography
There's a strong emotional attachment to the stage
We performed it this time but
I'm the only one left among the members who first performed it
First, I thought it was important to share my feelings towards the stage
That's why I asked the members performing today
To think of it as though it's their own stage, one they received
And perform with that in mind
I think everyone took that to heart and performed well
And I think that was conveyed to our fans who were watching today
Okay, let's confirm the details for the performance
You were probably already sent this through email but
It might be better to use the tambourine more
You might move around while singing but
Please make sure you still face towards the cameras
Yes!
Since it's the first song
Let's start off with energetic smiles
- And for "Mango"...
- For "Mango No. 2"
It's okay even if you want to fool around more
It's okay even if all of you do that
At the moment it feels a bit low energy, so let's pump it up a bit
When it comes to facial expressions, think of "Pinocchio Gun" but cuter
Even if you make funny faces, it's totally alright
It's the only song where we can fool around
You can show a different side of you there
Then it's "Te wo tsunaginagara"
Make sure you keep standing there until the cameras go elsewhere, until the very end
Since they told us they won't film us while we're moving around
It's okay even if you're late to your position, please prioritise that
Should we say "Yes"?
"Yes" is probably fine
"Yes! I'm XX! Please be good to me!"
But if everyone says the same thing it might be too much
Maybe we should drop the last bit?
Let's go with "Yes! I'm XX!"
And then just wave, let's go with that
The rest could just cheer on
Like calling their names
Kind of like what fans usually do for us
To liven things up
Once the 1st row is done, they should separate
We'll do it for the 6th person
The 2nd row will do the same
Then we'll return, say "that was the 16 of us"
And "some members will go get ready"
Also those who have watched us
Told us that our expressions in "Innocence" were all over the place
Let's go with sexy, feminine-type of facial expressions
Like you're trying to seduce the people watching the screen
And for "Kayou Suiyou"
We should go with a "sexy" but "cold" feel
The lyrics are like that too
They're both sexy but with a contrast
For example it's okay to give out a smirk
For "Innocence"
Let's all go with the same feel in our expressions, thank you
I mentioned this during the rehearsal too
This is the first original stage we received as SKE
The members from that time are now mostly gone
But I'd like you to think of it as though it's your own stage
while performing today
Today, we can't hold hands, or even use a rope but
There's all that but
Let's all be aware of our fans who are watching on their screens
"While we can't link hands, our hearts are linked"
I hope we can convey that to our fans
Everyone, I'm counting on you
We can't link our hands, but our hearts are one
Let's make this a great show together
It's finally starting isn't it?
It's starting, oh no
It hasn't sunk in yet
Today, it is SKE48's 12th Anniversary Fest 2020 ~12 stages back-to-back~
Thank you for coming to the "Te wo tsunaginagara" stage
Before we begin our performances we would like to make a few requests to our guests today
During the performances, standing on your seat, or leaving your seat to run to the front are extremely dangerous
Thus, these behaviours are prohibited
It is prohibited to bring in any form of video and audio recording devices
And finally, please turn off your mobile phones
During the performances today, for the convenience of production
The emergency exit lights in the audience seats will be turned off
In the event of a disaster
Lights will be turned on and you will be guided by the staff
However, please take note of the emergency exits in advance
Also, to minimise the risk of virus transmission
It is prohibited to speak loudly and to stand up
We would appreciate it if you could show your support through hand clapping and penlights
Yes, personally this is my first appearance in "Te wo tsunaginagara" in a long time
I am very nervous
And also to those of you here who were selected as audience
For some of you it may be the first time in a while to see us perform in person
There is some physical distance between us but
Our hearts are linked
Everyone, please enjoy the performances as much as you can
Please enjoy it until the end
This was SKE48 Team S Matsui Jurina
Without further ado, the performances will begin shortly
Thank you
Oh no what should I do, I'm too nervous
The first chorus goes this way, the second chorus goes this way
Okay! Thank you so much
Thank you!
My mother said she'll be watching
I'd like to take a final sip, a drink please?
Okay, thank you
I'm seriously nervous, what should I do, I'm in trouble
I'll do my best
I'll be going
Everything from that time in the past as well as the present
I'll show it today
"Chime (wa Love Song)" was a dangerous one, I was tearing up
Everyone's about to be surprised
I'm counting on you two
It's like this right?
I finished it!
I did it!
- That was super cool
- Really?
I made a point to make it sexy
How are you now? Has the nervousness gone away?
I'm still really nervous
But I'm curious what the reaction is going to be, after I performed "Ame no Pianist"
I'll be looking forward to it, as I'm changing
Because Jurina-san was in the middle
This is how she sucks up to me
- Because the cameras are rolling
- She's sucking up
But it's likeable
It's funny
I like that about her
- She's always cheerful
- Please use this footage
Thank you so much
Thank you! It ended smoothly
We finished it
I got emotional there towards the end
I remembered everything that happened until now
Like things about graduated members
It was really linked with the lyrics
It made me remember all that
Also we're in these circumstances where we can't really meet our fans
When I thought of that...
I became sad
And tears started to well up
I told myself not to cry
I wanted to finish everything properly with a smile
But I failed
Just goes to show that there are so many songs I have an emotional attachment to
And I guess with that my feelings came through to everyone
To have been able to do this for 12 years
It's all thanks to the members, the staff
And the fans
There were many, countless people
Of course my family too
It's because I had all of their support
That I have what I have today
It's a concert that reminded me of that again
- Thank you!
-Thank you!
Thank you~!
- Thank you, good work today
- Thank you
During the performance, you two were the people who smiled at each other the most
That might be true
- We made a lot of eye contact
- I was watching her closely
We worked together for a long time
That's why there were such moments, where we're compatible
And today I got to see Kamata's nice belly too
You're blushing
- Please praise me, Kamata, for not running away
- Good girl, I ran away
- Because I can't wear my old costumes anymore
- Is that so?
You were in elementary school that time right?
Yeah, it's tight around my bottom, and my chest too
- I was surprised to see Jurina-san's "Aozora Kataomoi" costume
- Yeah it's crazy isn't it?
One time we had to wear the original member costumes
We looked at the pants together, and went "are these leggings"?
I feel like I'll fall asleep immediately
Thank you!
We've finished the "Te wo tsunaginagara" stage!
To our fans, thank you so much for these cute flowers!
It's the best! I love you!
Bye bye!
I'm going home! Good night! Bye!
See you soon!
[To be continued]
[English subtitles by @kujirajuunigou]