Good morning!
Let's blow it off properly, my feet
Let's go after this is done
This is how we did the shoot
One shot after the other
I injured my right hand so
I tried my best to hide my right hand
Here's the changing room
And over here, to help inform us when we're appearing
Like the setlist, where to go, the order of MCs
Inoue, Kitagawa, Sakamoto, Nakamura...
JurinaJurina (lol)
There will be two Jurinas (lol)
Sometimes we see things like this
Because they make many of these, it's hard on the staff
Thanks for always helping us
I hope our feelings of gratitude will reach you all
Finally
I'd like us to unite our hearts and sing together
Please listen to this song
"Boku wa shitteiru"
That wraps up the 12th anniversary special concert rehearsal
After this, it's the "Theatre no Megami" stage, then the "Ramune no Nomikata" stage
And finally the 12th anniversary SP
Until the end
So that everyone can have a grand celebration for SKE's 12th anniversary
I humbly request your cooperation
- Okay, Jurina
- Yes!
Can we please increase the volume of the in-ear mic?
- Okay, Jurina let's do "Boku wa shitteiru"
-Yes, please
That was good
Thank you very much
What kind of "making of" is this?
They said this might be used for "something"
- They'll definitely use this
- Yeah
Ojuri is a good egg
(t/n: Suzuran uses a bunch of slang from here on)
We're chums (lol)
- It sounds like I'm making you say that
- We're great chums
"Chums?" They'll think we're one of those try-hards
Because we get along well, okemaru?
Jurina-san, are these
The things you mentioned when you came in earlier? For the staff?
Yes, these are for the staff
Some gifts for them
I always drink these
Energy drinks
After this I'm mostly free
I'm just hammering into my head the things in the rehearsal once again
And I'll just relax a little, have a meal
And get ready to go all out for the performance
"Boku wa shitteiru" is
Sung in the order you joined the group
We're going by the generations
And somehow, really
Even the song
Is about things like hoping for our hard work to be rewarded
Or hoping that we'll be able to smile in the future
These are the thoughts of fans towards us
The lyrics are about that
So that's why
When I sing that song
I get strength from the song, the lyrics
Like, I hope the fans would think of us this way
And even the part where the 1st gens would sing
There used to be many members
But now it's just me
Part of me does feel sad about it
But it's a very important song
- This style might be good
- This one?
Jurina-san, I'm asking out of curiosity but
Earlier weren't you were humming a bunch of songs?
How many songs do you have in your memory?
How many songs...
If we count not only SKE but also AKB
There might be around 1000 songs?
1000 songs and their choreography
Was it that many? I'm not sure
There are some that I haven't performed that much but remember
Maybe I can say 500 songs?
I look like a toy poodle
I like toy poodles
We don't get the impression that you make mistakes often when it comes to lyrics or dance
But what's that like in reality?
For me, probably
Up till now, I think the number of times I've made mistakes is pretty low
Even the members around me often tell me things like that
But even if I do make a mistake, I think I cover it up well
I don't act like I've made a mistake
I'm becoming numb
- Hmm?
- I'm becoming numb
[inaudible]
Yes, that's right
I might feel relieved later too
Like "it's over!"
A Korean fan gave this to me
Korean makeup
I'm sure that made you happy
Yeah, Korean fans send me lots of things like this
I went with pink today
Usually when you're walking around town
Do you get spotted by your fans?
When I'm walking
When I'm walking in the streets they do call out to me
Because I'm the type who's fine when people do that
Usually I end up talking with them
With my fans
Even when I haven't put on any makeup
I'd tell them, sorry for my bare face
Yeah usually I'd talk to them
Sometimes there would be people who just happen to know me but are not my fans, they'd come speak to me
For those people
I'd try to meet them
And get them to know me as a person
In the hopes they'd end up liking me
It's not something I dislike at all
Especially when I meet families with young kids
I'd go "hooray!!", because I love kids
I can't do it right now but
When I see babies I'd go "so cute" and poke their cheeks
I like the cheeks of young kids
So I'd always try and squish their cheeks
Also, when I find a cute kid
I'd always tell them
Come join SKE when you grow up
I'd be scouting them
I was sent a really nostalgic photo
- Can we see it?
- Isn't that too cute?
That's too cute
It might have been good to go with this hairstyle
The ones we're doing today
There are many songs I'm quite used to singing and dancing
So I'm probably not as nervous today
Should I say nervousness?
More like the fear of making a mistake? But probably not fear either
But I do get nervous
Since it's like a milestone this time
Because it's my last (SKE anniversary)
So you're saying your performance might go better than usual today?
Hmm, I wonder about that
Normally, regardless of whether I perform on a big or small stage
I try to keep my feelings the same
That's the aim, but sometimes I do naturally get pumped up
- For "Pareo wa Emerald", Jurina-san please take the first wave
- Yes!
- Ah, excuse me
- Yes, please go ahead
It's SKE's 12th anniversary
I may be the only member left who's been here from the start
But since it's a festival celebrating SKE's 12th year
I hope that you all try to feel as though you've been here from the start
When you perform on stage today
How should I say this
There may be members who feel like it's someone else's celebration
Because some of you may have only joined recently
But we're all one team here
We're all SKE members here, please think of it as your own celebration
I hope each of you keeps that in mind when you stand on the stage today
And convey our gratitude to the fans
Thank you
- It's your last mic for the day
- That's right
Mic no. 15, it's 15 (ikou)
There used to be a lot more 1st gens when we did "Boku wa shitteiru"
Then it became fewer and fewer
Like recently I ended up coming to the front
This time too
Senpai corner!
- Senpai corner
- Corner?
We've all been here around 12 years
But not much has changed since last year
(In Nagoya-ben) Not much has changed since last year
- But I thought you two wouldn't be here
- Yeah you're right
We thought you wouldn't be here
- Thanks to you two for staying on...
- It should have been my last day today
- Oh yeah, that's right!
- Yeah, it was to be my final day
- You did say it was going to be the anniversary
- Yes, that was supposed to be the last day
But how do you feel about this?
- It's pretty weird
- I'm sure
There's some good about this but...
But I did "Tetsuna" yesterday
Had things been normal, I couldn't have performed the full Tetsuna
Once we quit we can't do such fun things anymore
- That's kind of sad
- Yeah, that's true
- Sorry for being part of this conversation
- It's all good
You memorised by watching?
That's amazing!
Wow!
That's perfect
Eh, it's perfect!
The truth is you want to be in KII right? (lol)
I'll sing while making this face through the whole thing
Ah, so you actually want to be in Team E? (lol)
You want to be in Team E?
Everyone, we have 1 more important announcement to make
Please watch this video
Yes, there will be a new SKE48 single
About that, Jurina-san
Yes
Did you see it?
I saw it
It's my graduation single
That's right!!
So that's rearly string?
(t/n: Makki is mispronouncing a word here)
"Early spring" you mean?
You do that sometimes, don't you? (lol)
(t/n: this is SKE's last single name)
Please tell us your thoughts
Yes, the truth is
Today was supposed to be my last day
Today, on 5 October
I was supposed to have my graduation stage
It was supposed to be the day I leave my idol days behind
And walk towards a new start
But well, Matsui Jurina is still here to stay
There will still be new starts for me from now on
I'm happy that things were decided like this
And for SKE, it's been a while since we've had a new single too
And since it's my last one too, I'd like it to be an SKE-like song
And also, by the way
It's probably weird to segue into this like this but
But since we're here
I'd like to make another announcement
Well, I mentioned this earlier but
It was supposed to be my last day but things got postponed
And following this
About my activities with SKE
Or for things after my graduation
I'd like to share all kinds of things with the fans
And have more fun together
So I talked with the staff, and the result of the discussion is
That I, Matsui Jurina
Will start a YouTube channel!
Juritube?
Eh, could it be that
The cameras going around filming, are they...?
That might be related (lol)
Ah, there they are! (lol)
If you see them, make sure you say hello
Well, all good times must come to an end
We'd like to perform our final song
How do I put this, for me
The new single will be released in spring
That means I'll probably be leaving the group around that time
For next year's 13th anniversary
I won't be here, it might be the same for Churi too
You might not be here, I'm not sure though
I've had my 1st anniversary since announcing my graduation
Well we don't know about that but
The group will soon have no 1st gens left
But I hope everyone continues to liven things up
For the 13th anniversary, I'd like to come watch if I can
I hope everyone livens things up
But also our gratitude towards people who support us
From the members who couldn't be here today due to timing
And those who have already departed from the group
Including all of these
We'd like to perform our next, final song
To convey our gratitude to all of you
Please listen to it
"Boku wa shitteiru"
Yes, the reason I was able to keep going for 12 years was...
But actually in the middle
Honestly, there were times I have thought about quitting
How should I put this, I'm easily misunderstood
I'm the type to react in certain ways in some situations
There were many things that I was the first to do
I did things that were without precedent
There were many things like that
And because of that
People formed various opinions about me
When I heard about such things I did get sad
And there were moments I thought of giving up
But I can go on if there's even a single person
Who is cheered up by watching me
And supports me as a fan
Through letters, comments
And coming to handshake events
These things really come through to me
It's because I've had fans like that
That's one of the reasons
And of course, the members are a huge factor
There was no way I could have done this alone
We experienced both pain and joy together
Right now SKE is comprised of my juniors
It was really fun to watch my juniors grow
At first I was like the youngest child
Along the way I started feeling like the older sister or parent
Also, my family
When my mother was young
She'd wanted to sing and dance
As she wasn't able to do it
She always told me she was happy to see her daughter living her dream
That's why rather than doing this for myself
I felt like doing this for other people
There were many reasons like that
It's because of those reasons that I was able to do my best
Thank you!
[SKE48 and Matsui Jurina are not over yet...]